Rocío Martín

Cornelis Trooststraat 24-2 1072JE, Amsterdam romartinaqua@gmail.com, +31 628102994
LinkedIn | Github

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an entrepreneur-turned-developer with +20 years of experience in a wide range of technology-related fields and companies. I look to bring my knowledge and expertise and learn additional skills. I have learned coding skills with Code Institute, I joined them in 2019-2020, where I had to work on different projects, using different tools and languages to solve problems and build up products. I am looking for a position where I can have an impact, using the skills and experience I have acquired in the past to create value for my team and the end users. I prefer working in an e-commerce, data analytics consultation agency or in sales where I believe my background can help me hit the ground running.

EDUCATION

Code Institute

Full Stack Software Developer Diploma APR, 2019 – SEP, 2020

SCRUMstudy

Scrum Fundamentals Certified 18 DEC. 2019

Colegio de Politólogos y Sociólogos de Madrid

Master Degree in Health, Safety and Environment at Work (HSE) OCT. 2006 – MAR 2007

Universidad Pontificia de Salamanca, campus Madrid

Sociology Degree SEP. 1994 – JUN 1998

TECHNICAL SKILL SET

Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Data Bases MySQL, MongoDB, AWS,

Frameworks/Libraries React, jQuery, Flask, Django

Data Analysis Advanced Google Analiytics

Version Control Git, Githiub

UX Tools Bootstrap, Figma, Balsamiq, Materialize

OTHER LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Linkedin.com/in/rocio-martin-2680138/details/certifications/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneur-Founder-Urban Agriculture Consultant

Biphiliacs BV Sep 2016 - Jan 2023

Experimental Organic Coffee and Tea House, with Urban Aquaponics Farm and Upcycling projects. From Jan 2020 I worked as Urban Agriculture Consultant, providing innovative solutions to fit the needs of diverse clients looking for challenges in Urban Agriculture. Hosting workshops to Grow food in urban environments.

Aquaponics Specialist

Mediamatic Foundation Sep 2014 - Dec 2016

Exploring the possibilities and challenges that new technology offers to art, design and society. Designer and maintenance of Urban Aquaponics Farm.

Contract Administrator

Cisco Systems International B.V. Mar 2012 - May 2014

Successful management of the country enablement related contract (EMEAR and APAC) for signature, verifying that the Cisco approval process was followed fully and correctly, scheduling time with the signatory. Contracts administration from different areas of the business (Manufacturing, Licensing, Sales Agreements, Cisco Capital, etc.). Validating key data entered the Contract Management System by the Legal team. Attaching scanned contract to proper Contract Record Archiving Expired/Terminated paper contracts with appropriate retention period.

Call Center Representative

ACN Jul 2011 - Dec 2011

Call center supporting ACN Representatives, versed in customer support in a high calls volume environment. Superior computer skills and telephone etiquette. Responding to website users, scaling legal and compliance issues. Managing payments online from Rep's fees.

Sales Support Specialist

Konica Minolta Medical Graphics BV Jun 2008 - Dec 2010

Inside Sales Support to different Konica branch offices in Europe with excellent verbal and written communication skills and strong computer and CRM/SAP experience. Successful at continually meeting or exceeding sales and service objectives. Expertise in customizing approaches to fit the businesses, markets and target customers. In permanent contact with the technical team in Japan to deliver Software Licenses for medical devices.

Technical Customer Support Representative

TomTom Mar 2007 - May 2008

Technology-oriented with the ability to deliver product fixes and troubleshoot technical problems quickly. Supporting technical inquiries of end customers, by phone and mail, solving technical, financial and marketing issues, giving information and opening RMAs of fault devices.

Sales Engineer

PROTOS INFORMATICA Y TELECOMUNICACION SL Dec 2004 - Jan 2007

Independent and motivated Sales Representative with a proven track record of building and growing sales territories in competitive environments. Dedicated to building rapport and maintaining loyal customer relationships through understanding needs and creating individual solutions. Offering deep technical acumen with strong communication skills to help customers understand GPS Fleet Management products.

Sales Engineer

Diode España S.A Sep 2003 - Oct 2004

Excellent business acumen and a proven history of driving technical sales and revenue growth. Friendly and dynamic with the natural ability to build key relationships through communication, customer service, and negotiation skills. Ability to lead and motivate teams to execute business opportunities and close sales in fast-paced Rocío Martín - page 2 environments with tight deadlines. New Wacecom distributor from summer 2003 invited me to move to Diode as a new distributor for Spanish market.

Personal Assistant and Sales Representative

Xacom Comunicaciones Jan 1999 - Sep 2003

Hard-working, multi-tasking Executive Assistant with outstanding telephone, scheduling and documentation skills. In 2001 I started a talented Sales Representative career with excellent lead generation potential. Highly effective and knowledgeable in techniques used to close sales opportunities.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

One fact (outside of work) about me...

I discovered my passion for programming thanks to my curiosity, where I used to use Wix.com to create websites for me and others and I wanted to learn how to do it myself. With a huge commercial mind, I like to work in E-Commerce and/or Real Estate projects because of my previous background and expertise. My main hobby is growing food in urban environments where I experimented with different techniques like Aquaponics and Hydroponics growing vegetables and mushrooms, playing with Arduino to monitor my systems. Continuously joining webinars and courses to update my skills, improving and learning. Lately very interested and focus on SaaS, Data Science and Web3.

PORTFOLIO

E-Commerce project (Python/Django)



Housing Project (JavaScript)

